<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">BYBall</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="menu_settings">Settings</string>
	<string name="textoajuda">
	    <![CDATA[
<!DOCTYPE html>
<html>
<head>
	<meta charset=\"UTF-8\"/>
	<meta name=\"viewport\" content=\"width=device-width\" />
	
    <style>
		body {
			font-family: Arial;
			font-size: 1.5em;
			color: black; 
		}
		.negrito {
			font-weight: bold;
		}

	  a:link {
		color:black;
		font-weight: bold;
		text-decoration:underline;
		}
		a:visited {
		color:yellow;
		text-decoration:none;
		}
		a:hover {
		color:cyan;
		text-decoration:underline;
		}
		a:active {
		color:#00FF00;
		text-decoration:underline;
		background-color:#000000;
	}

	</style>    
	
</head>
<body>
<h3>Backyard Ball</h3>


<h3>Version 2.0</h3>


Backyard Ball is a game of skill, simple yet challenging. It is a mistake to think that this is a easy game. 
It has levels that offer an experience of increasing difficulty, resulting in a very entertaining game.
<br/>
Backyard Ball uses the library <a href=\"http://box2d.org/\">\"Box2D\"</a>, created by Erin Catto. It also uses several free images from 
<a href=\"http://openclipart.org/\">Open Clippart</a>.
<h3>Objective</h3>
The objective of the game is to knock down all the objects that are on the other side of the \"wall\". 
These objects are mounted on poles or boards, which, depending on the level, can be mobile.
<br/>
There is a time constraint for each level:

<dl>
<dt class=\"negrito\">Levels 1 to 5</dt>
<dd>60 seconds</dd>
<dt class=\"negrito\">Levels 6 to 10</dt>
<dd>70 seconds</dd>
<dt class=\"negrito\">Levels 11 to 15</dt>
<dd>60 seconds</dd>
<dt class=\"negrito\">Levels 16 to 18</dt>
<dd>60 seconds</dd>
<dt class=\"negrito\">Levels 19 to 20</dt>
<dd>90 seconds</dd>
<dt class=\"negrito\">Levels 21 to 25</dt>
<dd>60 seconds</dd>
<dt class=\"negrito\">Levels 26 to 30</dt>
<dd>90 seconds</dd>

</dl>

<h3>Gameplay</h3>
The ball must be \"kicked\" by you, toward the other side of the wall. To \"kick\", touch on the ball and, 
without lifting your finger, drag to where you want. When you release your finger, it will apply a force to the ball 
and the ball will move.
<br/>
The direction in which you drag your finger away and length of the drag determine, respectively, the direction of the \"kick\" 
and the force being applied to the ball. The further the drag, the greater the force.
<br/>
The game setting is surrounded by the four sides: ceiling, floor, wall right and left wall.
<br/>
There can be only one \"kick\" per move. Each play can end one of four ways:
<ol>
<li>It hit one of the targets (bottles, bottle, medicine bottle, glass, can, bottle of ketchup etc). 
If the object falls, it will be considered a hit.</li>
<li>Hit the ground. In this case, the ball is moved back to the starting position on the other side of the wall;</li>
<li>Hit a target, but out of order (in some levels there is hitting order). 
In this case, the ball will bounce back and the object will be restored;</li>
<li>Could not get past the wall.</li>
</ol>
<br/><span class=\"negrito\">Tips</span>
<ul>
<li>Touch with the index finger tip, to get best result;</li>
<li>Calculate the force being applied. Less force means more control;</li>
<li>Make the ball bounce in other objects (walls, poles etc).</li>
<li>If the ball gets stuck on the left side, in 1 second it will be released to you.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Levels</h3>
Toplay a level, it must be released, what happens if the previous level was successfully completed.
 Each level has an expected average. If you complete the level (dropping all objects) within the average, 
receives a silver medal, which becomes the icon of the level where your time will be displayed.
<br/>
If you complete the level with a time less than the average, receives a gold medal. And if you finish with above average time, 
receive a bronze medal.
<br/>
To unlock the next level, the average of their times in the previous level must be at least equal to the expected average.
<br/><br/>
<span class=\"negrito\">Expected averages by level</span><br/>
<dl>
<dt class=\"negrito\">Levels de 1 to 5</dt>
<dd>12 seconds</dd>
<dt class=\"negrito\">Levels de 6 to 10</dt>
<dd>18 seconds</dd>
<dt class=\"negrito\">Levels de 11 to 15</dt>
<dd>22 seconds</dd>
<dt class=\"negrito\">Levels de 16 to 20</dt>
<dd>30 seconds</dd>
<dt class=\"negrito\">Levels de 21 to 25</dt>
<dd>30 seconds</dd>
<dt class=\"negrito\">Levels de 26 to 30</dt>
<dd>30 seconds</dd>

</dl>
<br/>
<h3>Constraints</h3>
There is a hitting order in some levels, which forces you to hit the targets in that sequence. From level 6 and beyond, you have to be careful to drop the objects in the expected order.
<br/>
The order appears in the upper left corner, just below the \"EXIT\" button. There is a order number and the objects appear to be hit in that order. 
Levels of 6 to 10, you have to hit two objects in each order. In the levels beyond 6, the order is individual.
<br/>
If you hit an object out of its order, it will reappear and you can suffer a penalty. 
In the levels of 11 onwards, every 3 times you hit an object out of order, another object will be reset. 
For example, let\'s assume that you have dropped a soda can and then missed 3 times, in this case, the soda can appears again, delaying your game time.
<br/>
At levels 21 onwards, there is the concept of \"Forbidden Object\", which, if knocked down, makes you miss the level (a symbol with a red hand appears). The forbidden object is the last in the order list, inside a red oval and with a black band.
<br/>
<h3>Controls</h3>
When you enter the game, you will see buttons with the level numbers. If the level is locked, a small padlock will appear below its number.
<br/>
If the level is open and has not been played yet, will appear in gray. If you it has already been played, your \"medal\" 
(gold, silver or bronze) will be shown, and the shortest time you completed it. In both cases, you can tap the button and enter the level to play.
<br/>
There are three buttons in the home screen: \"help\", \"next\" and \"previous\". The \"next\" and \"previous\" buttons have two red arrows as icons
that appear below the levels, and serve to show the next page of levels or return to previous page.
<br/>
Within each level, there is an \"EXIT\" button, which returns to the Home screen. 
After completing the level, either by shooting down all the targets, or by timeout, a button will appear offering 
the \"Replay\" level.
If you successfully complete, appear two other buttons: 
one to the next level and another to share the results. 
You can share the results in various types of social networks and media, 
such as: Google+, Facebook, Twitter, SMS, Gmail, email etc.. To share, you need to get on the Internet.
<br/>
<h3>Author</h3>
<br/>Designed and programmed by: <span class=\"negrito\">Cleuton Sampaio</span>.
<br/>
It is offered to you by <a href=\"http://www.thecodebakers.org\" class=\"negrito\">The Code Bakers</a> and <a href=\"http://www.indiegamerbrasil.com\" class=\"negrito\">Indie Gamer Brasil</a>.
<br/>
Learn to make a game like this reading the book: \"<a href=\"http://www.indiegamerbrasil.com\" class=\"negrito\">Manual do Indie Game Developer</a>\", 
published by: <a href=\"http://www.lcm.com.br\" class=\"negrito\">Ci&ecirc;ncia Moderna</a>.
<br/>

</body>
</html>
	    
		]]>
	</string>
	<string name="eula">
	    <![CDATA[
	    Please: read all the text and mark the checkbox at the end. It will only appear one time per version of the game.
	    \r\n
End user license agreement:\r\n
\r\n
\r\nThe use of software "Backyard Ball" (THE SOFTWARE) is governed by the terms of this license, which is a
implicit agreement between the person who will install and use the software (THE USER) and the person who developed the
software (THE AUTHOR).
\r\n
\r\nIf you disagree with the terms of this license, please uninstall the software.
\r\n
\r\nIf you, the USER, proceed and use the SOFTWARE (subject of this license), you, the USER acknowledges and agrees to all 
terms of this license.
\r\n
1) Recognition of copyright:
\r\n
\r\n(C) 2013 by Cleuton Sampaio de Melo Jr.
\r\n
\r\nBy using the SOFTWARE ("Backyard Ball") you, hereafter designated "THE USER", acknowledges the authorship and the resulting
copyright by Cleuton Sampaio de Melo Jr, hereinafter designated "THE AUTHOR".
\r\n
If you do not agree to recognize these rights or any other terms of this license, you must uninstall
software and not use it in any way.
\r\n
\r\n2)License terms:
\r\n
\r\nThrough this document, the USER received a personal and non transferable license to use the SOFTWARE, compound by 
the software package containing the compiled code, and resources such as images, texts, sounds etc..
\r\n
\r\nThe use is limited by several constraints mentioned below. Violation of any of these restrictions implies
immediate termination of this license.
\r\n
\r\n3) License Restrictions:
\r\n
\r\nTHE USER CAN NOT: Sell, distribute, rent or make available this software (and documentation) except when expressly authorized
by THE AUTHOR. In case of an authorized transfer of this license, the person receiving the SOFTWARE must agree to
the terms of this license.
\r\n
\r\nTHE USER CAN NOT: Disassemble the SOFTWARE package, substitute its components, and or use its components (in whole or part) 
in other products. likewise, the USER can not use reverse engineering to try to get access to the source code.
Also, the USER can not create derivatives of the SOFTWARE without the express permission of the AUTHOR, as well as
can not change in any way the content of the SOFTWARE package, for example (but not limited to): add  new code or 
unlock features. The USER can not change manually or by other software, any of the SOFTWARE package files.
\r\n
\r\nTHE USER CAN NOT: Change or remove this license or any documentation or pictures on the package SOFTWARE.
\r\n

\r\n4) Termination of License
\r\n
\r\nThe USER may terminate the license at any time by simply uninstalling and destroying any copies of the SOFTWARE 
\r\nin his (or hers) possession. There is no obligation to refund any amount by the AUTHOR.
\r\n
\r\nTHE AUTHOR may terminate the license at any time, proved that the USER has violated these terms.
\r\n
\r\n5) Limited Warranty:
\r\n
\r\nThe SOFTWARE and documentation are distributed as they are ("AS IS"), without any guarantee of performance and applicability
for any particular use.
\r\n
\r\nDespite AUTHOR\'s efforts to create a SOFTWARE that meets its purpose, the warranty against defects is excluded from this
license. THE AUTHOR does not warrant that the software do not have defects or performance problems, especially due to
large number of platforms on which the SOFTWARE may be executed.
\r\n
\r\nThe distribution of the SOFTWARE is done "on line" by GOOGLE PLAY, so any complaints about the unavailability
and defects in the software package, caused by transfer, shall be made to the administration of GOOGLE PLAY.
\r\n
\r\nTHE AUTHOR provides contact information in their own product page on GOOGLE PLAY, so any contact should
be done only by designated channels there.
\r\n
\r\nTHE AUTHOR is not obligated to develop new versions or updates of the SOFTWARE.
\r\n
\r\n6) Questions not covered in this license:
\r\n
\r\nIt is the jurisdiction of the forum of the municipality of Rio de Janeiro, State of Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, to resolve any questions not
clarified by this license.
\r\n  
	    
	    ]]>
	</string>
	<string name="concordo">I agree</string>
	<string name="prosseguir">Proceed</string>
	<string name="titulopontos">These are your best scores until now:\r\n</string>
	<string name="nivel">Level</string>
	<string name="sair">Back</string>
	<string name="sharesubject">I beat the game in Backyard Ball</string>
	<string name="sharetext">I beat the level: %1$d of the BackyardBall game in %2$d seconds!</string>
	<string name="sharetitle">Share using</string>
	<string name="app_id">636241249723568</string>
	<string name="postfacebook">Post sent to facebook.</string>
	<string name="postothers">Post sent to %1$s.</string>
	<string name="posturl">http://indiegamerbrasil.com</string>
	<string name="posterror">Could not post to %1$s. Verify network connection.</string>
	<string name="postnonetwork">Can not post to %1$s. You must connect to Internet.</string>
</resources>